stv.tv 2018-10-21

# Terms and Conditions | Terms of Use | MySTV

Welcome to STV’s digital products and services (together the “Services”). These Terms of Use apply whether you have joined STV or are just visiting.

THESE TERMS OF USE ARE IMPORTANT FOR YOU AND FOR US. THEY EXPLAIN:

• your rights and responsibilities

• our responsibilities to you

• how we expect you to interact with our Services and with other users

By using our Services, you are presumed to have read and understood these Terms of Use, and accepted that they apply whether you have joined or are visiting STV’s Services. They will change from time to time, so please take a fresh look every so often. Where any additional terms apply, they will be highlighted to you.

**1) Who delivers the Services to me?**

We are STV Central Limited, a company registered in Scotland no. 172149. If you have any queries, you can contact us at [enquiries@stv.tv](mailto:viewerenquiries@stv.tv), phone us on +44 (0)141 300 3000, or write to us at STV, Pacific Quay, Glasgow G51 1PQ.

**2) What are the Services?**

The Services are our website [www.stv.tv](https://www.stv.tv/); our STV Player (carrying both (i) live simultaneous online transmission of our television broadcast services; (ii) our catch-up services and (iii) certain STV archive programmes); our mobile apps (including the STV News App); and our newsletters. These Terms of Use apply regardless of the device or platform you use to access our Services. Please note that not all Services or features may be available across every platform or device.

We aim to provide constant and uninterrupted access to the Services, but we do not take responsibility for issues outside our control, such as internet or connection issues. Specifically we do not guarantee:

• the availability of the Services on each and every device or platform all of the time

• that any technical issues that arise can be resolved quickly

• that the Services are error, virus or bug free

**3) What do we mean when we refer to “Content” on the Services?**

Content can be programmes, video, audio, text, images, either owned by us or licensed to us to use.

**4) Whose Content is it?**

All copyright, trademarks and other intellectual property rights in the Content belong to us or our licensors. The Content is protected by various intellectual property rights, such as copyright and trade mark laws. You may not reproduce or distribute any Content except as provided below.

You may only use the Content for your personal, non-commercial use. However, provided they are credited to STV, you may publish short excerpts or summaries of a published article accompanied by a hyperlink which takes the reader to the whole article on our Services.

Your use of the Content must not (in our sole opinion) bring, or be likely to bring, STV into disrepute, or otherwise cause any loss or damage to STV.

Content on our Services may contain statements and opinions which are not our own, and with which we do not necessarily agree. We do not guarantee the accuracy or completeness of all the Content.

**5) Accessing our Services**

Here are the ways to access our Services.

  1. Visit our web-site at [www.stv.tv](https://www.stv.tv/)

  2. Download our Apps (including our STV Player App, and our STV News App)

  3. Subscribe to e-newsletters

  4. Enter a competition

If you join our Services, you will be opening an STV account, and you will be asked to enter your email address and a password ("Log-in details"), along with your name, date of birth and home address. You should keep your Log-in details confidential. Do not allow anyone else to use them. You are responsible for all activity that occurs under your Log-in details.

For e-newsletters around our online news service, at a minimum, you need to provide your email address.

**You must be 16 or over to join and open an STV account, or to subscribe to any newsletter.**

You must provide a current email address and accurate personal details. You must not abuse any functionality of the Services, or other users, nor pass yourself off as another user. STV may require you to provide evidence to verify that your personal details are correct and that you are using our Services in accordance with our Terms of Use.

All information that you provide to us will be held and processed in accordance with our Privacy Policy.

**6) What I should know about using the STV Player?**

**Age restriction**

You must be 16 or over to join and access the STV Player.

**Geo-restrictions**

We apply "geo-blocking" measures to prevent access to some Content in cases where rights restrictions apply. Specifically, there is some Content which will not be accessible if you are located outside the central and north regions of Scotland (where we broadcast our Channel 3 service), and/or outside the United Kingdom.

You agree not to circumvent any geo-blocking measures or to access, or attempt to access, such Content if you are located in areas to which we have prevented access.

**Programme Suitability and Parental Controls**

Some of the Content available on the STV Player video on-demand service may contain material unsuitable for under 18s, or may be of a sensitive nature. We use different systems to identify such material.

• Where it is unsuitable for **under 16s** , we endeavour to identify it by flagging a symbol “G” (for guidance).

• Where is it unsuitable for **under 18s** (or of a sensitive nature, generally) we provide guidance notes.

We have built parental controls into the STV Player. It’s up to you to set the parental controls if any children have access to your device. Once set, they will prevent the viewing of Content labelled with a “G” symbol from that device unless a 4 figure PIN is entered.

**“Catch Up” and archive Content is not live**

Catch up and archive Content available on the STV Player is not live. Therefore, please do not respond to any invitation to enter any competition, phone-in, vote, quiz or any other interaction, as the time for the interaction may have come to an end. If you do so, you may still be charged, and your entry/contribution may be too late, and not included, or considered.

**Live streaming**

When we are live streaming, or simulcasting our television channels over the internet, there is a delay but the service is as near live as possible. Please bear this in mind when interacting with our Services.

**Removal/Amendment**

Please note that we may amend/remove Content available on our STV Player at any time without notice.

**7) How may I use the Services?**

You agree to use the Services only for non-commercial, lawful purposes, and in a manner that does not infringe the rights of third parties, or restrict or inhibit the use and enjoyment of the Services by any other user.

Specifically, you agree you shall not:

• de-compile, reverse engineer, reproduce, copy, distribute, license or sell the Services and/or the Content (or any part of them) in any way, other than as expressly permitted in these Terms of Use.

• use the Services for the transmission of any spam or computer viruses.

• do anything that brings (or in our opinion is likely to bring) STV into disrepute.

• embed, upload, or make any of the Services or Content available via any third party platform, website or service without STV’s prior consent.

• copy, reproduce or otherwise publish any of STV’s trademarks or logos.

• frame our website on other websites without our express permission.

**8) Interference with Content**

We may use technical measures for the security and protection of Content. You agree not to interfere with any such technical measures, or unlawfully access, or use, our servers, systems or Content, nor to attempt to do so.

**9) Interacting with the Services**

STV may invite you to interact with us through our Services from time to time. When you do so, for example by submitting or uploading comments, photographs, videos, audio clips, graphics, text, designs or any other type of contribution to the Services (each a **“Contribution”** ), you agree to comply with these Terms of Use and any additional terms that may be stated to apply in respect of any particular invitation to interact ( **“Specific Terms”** ). When you participate or contribute publicly, such as by posting comments or blogging for example, you must also comply with our House Rules, or we may block your account and stop you using this service.

Please note that you must be 16 or over to submit any Contribution to our Services (unless stated otherwise in any Specific Terms).

You (or those who have given you permission to use it) own any Contribution (including the intellectual property rights therein) that you submit and you may carry on using it.

By submitting a Contribution, you are granting to us (and in this section “us” includes other companies within the STV group of companies) a worldwide, royalty-free, non-exclusive, perpetual, irrevocable licence to use your Contribution on any media, platform or device (including on television) and to use, edit, prepare derivative works from and further distribute it across any media, platform or device throughout the world at any time, and to grant sub-licences. You also authorise STV to include some of your personal details together with your Contribution such as your name and location.

For editorial and compliance reasons, we might need to alter your Contribution and you authorise us to do so on the understanding that STV will not alter it in any way that misrepresents it.

You also confirm that:

• You are the either the owner of your Contribution or that you have all the necessary licences, rights, consents and permissions to authorise us to use your Contribution.

• You have obtained the consent of each person who appears in your Contribution to authorise us to use your Contribution. If any person under the age of 16 appears in your Contribution, you also confirm that you have the permission of such person’s parent or guardian.

• Your Contribution will not infringe or contravene any rights of any third parties (e.g. their entitlement to privacy or confidentiality) or contain anything which is defamatory, obscene, offensive or unlawful.

• You will not transfer files which contain viruses or other technologically harmful material.

If you submit a Contribution via a method which is available to the public, STV recommends that you do not disclose personal contact information such as your address or phone number.

Please note that STV reserves the right to require you to provide evidence of your age and eligibility.

**If you see any Contribution on the Services that you believe is offensive, defamatory or which infringes copyright or privacy, please contact us without delay at[enquiries@stv.tv](mailto:enquiries@stv.tv). In the case of comments, please raise a flag within the comment reporting system, or alternatively also contact us at enquiries@stv.tv.**

Whilst not moderating or controlling Contributions posted on our Services, we reserve the right to suspend or delete without notice any material which:

• we believe at our sole discretion to be detrimental to the enjoyment of the Services by any user;

• breaches these Terms of Use and/or the House Rules;

• is the subject of any copyright infringement notice; or

• brings, or is likely to bring, STV into disrepute, or otherwise cause any loss or damage to STV.

**10) Breach of Terms of Use**

We will determine, at our sole discretion, where there has been a breach of these Terms of Use. Where STV suspects that a breach has occurred, we may take such action as we deem appropriate which may include all, or any, of the following:

• Immediate, temporary or permanent withdrawal of your right to use the Services

• Immediate, temporary or permanent removal of any Contribution submitted by you

• Issue of a warning to you

• Commencement of legal proceedings against you

• Disclosure of information to law enforcement authorities

We exclude any liability for lawful actions taken by us in response to breaches of these Terms of Use and we reserve the right to seek compensation from you for any loss or damage we may suffer as a direct consequence of any breach by you of these Terms.

If you breach any of these Terms of Use, and we choose not to take action against you, that does not necessarily mean that we will waive any subsequent breaches by you. In addition, if we do not exercise the entire remedy available to us, we may still do so at a later date.

**11) Links to third party services**

You are solely responsible for evaluating the integrity of the operators of any third party websites accessed through the Services; the accuracy and completeness of any information contained on them; the value and authenticity of any goods or services offered through them, and their data collection and use policies.

**12) Featured Goods and Services**

STV, in association with one of its commercial partners may provide you with an opportunity to purchase featured goods and services from time to time via our Services. The contract for the relevant goods and services will be made directly between you and the relevant commercial partner and will be subject to the commercial partner’s terms and conditions. STV has no liability to you in respect of such goods and services.

**13) STV Appeal**

We host a micro-site on our Services that relates to the activities of STV Appeal, a Scottish Charitable Incorporated Organisation (Registered Charity Number SC042429) which has its principal office at Pacific Quay, Glasgow G51 1PQ. Although we work closely with STV Appeal it is an independent body for the purposes of Scottish charity law.

**14) Liability**

In no event shall we be liable for any claims, loss or damage, arising out of or in connection with your use of, or inability to use, the Services, including, without limitation, direct or indirect loss, consequential loss or damage, loss of profit or goodwill, or for loss arising from any errors or omissions in the Services, or in the Content.

Nothing in these Terms of Use excludes or limits any liability which may not be excluded by any applicable law.

**15) Law and Jurisdiction**

These Terms of Use shall be governed by and construed in accordance with Scots law. All disputes arising from them shall be submitted to the non-exclusive jurisdiction of the Scottish courts.

**Updated 22 May 2018**

**STV PRIVACY POLICY**

**INTRODUCTION**

This Privacy Policy applies to our digital products and services which include our website (www.stv.tv); our STV Player app; our news app and our newsletters (the “Services”), regardless of the platform you use to access them.

STV Central Limited (“STV” or “we”), a company registered in Scotland (company number SC172149), with registered office at Pacific Quay, Glasgow, G51 1PQ (“STV”) is the data controller responsible for looking after your personal data in line with data protection and privacy laws.

We are committed to ensuring your privacy and protecting the data we hold about you. This Privacy Policy explains how we do this and describes how and when STV collects and processes your personal data.

Please note that on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you we may provide additional privacy notices so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data (such as when you enter a competition or are invited to submit a Contribution).

By using the Services, you are presumed to have read and understood this Privacy Policy.

Please note that we update our Privacy Policy from time to time, so please take a fresh read through every so often. If we make significant changes, we will make that clear on our Services, or by some other means of contact such as email.

This privacy policy was last updated 22 May 2018.

**Contents**

  1. WHAT DATA IS COLLECTED AND WHEN?

  2. COOKIES AND OTHER TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES

  3. WHY WE COLLECT DATA

  4. HOW DO WE KEEP YOUR DATA SECURE?

  5. SHARING OF PERSONAL DATA

  6. MARKETING

  7. STV APPEAL

  8. LINKS TO OTHER SITES

  9. YOUR RIGHTS

  10. DATA RETENTION

  11. CONTACT US

**1)WHAT DATA IS COLLECTED AND WHEN?**

The type of information that may be collected will vary depending on which of our Services you are accessing and includes:

**Registration Data** : When you join STV by opening an account with us, we require your name, email address (and a password), postcode, and date of birth.

**Contact Data** :

• Where you enter a competition we will require your phone number (to notify you if you win) and full address where we need to arrange delivery of the prize.

• Any personal data you provide if you get in touch with us via email, phone or post with any comments or questions.

• Data you provide when you contribute to our Services (such as submit videos or photos to us (your “Contribution”));

**Analytical Data** : Information collected from cookies and other tracking methods about how you browse and use our Services including, for example, the frequency of your visits; the time you spend viewing our content; and what types of content you like most.

**Technical Data** : Includes internet protocol (IP) address, browser type and version, device identifiers, device advertising identifiers, location, operating system and platform; referring website addresses, date/time of visits, page view data, Internet service provider, click data, and information about your device including make, model and data connection type;

**Marketing Data** : Includes your instructions as to whether or not you wish to receive email marketing from STV and/or the Scottish Children’s Lottery (operated by STV group company STV ELM Limited).

**Data from Other Sources** : We combine information that you provide to us (and that we collect from time to time across different parts of our Services) with information that we receive from third parties. Companies such as advertisers you have bought a product or services from, who have obtained your permission to do, may share data with us. We also receive demographic profiling segmented information from Experian based on a combination of Experian proprietary, public and trusted third party sources.

**2)COOKIES AND OTHER TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES**

When using our Services, Technical Data and Analytical Data will automatically be collected by us and our authorised third parties about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns by using cookies and other similar technologies. We do this in order to operate, personalise, serve you with targeted ads and enhance the performance of our Services and to distinguish you from other users.

We use third party advertising networks and advertising servers to provide some of the ads you see on our Services. Such third parties place cookies or tracking technologies which remember that you have visited a website in order to provide you with targeted ads which are more relevant to you and your interests. This is often referred to as “Online Behavioural Advertising”. Please see our Cookie Policy for more information.

Note that when you download or use our apps on your mobile device or TV, information will be accessed from or stored to your device. This is done by using technologies similar to web browser cookies. These technologies carry out similar functions to web browser cookies, e.g. to enable the app to ‘remember’ you or to provide you with the content you have requested.

Please see our Cookie Policy for further details and how to manage your cookies.

**3)WHY WE COLLECT DATA**

Data protection and privacy laws permit us to collect and use your personal data on a limited number of grounds. The key grounds upon which we rely are:

• Where it is necessary for our **legitimate interests** and/or those of third parties with whom we share your data as described in this policy, and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests (please see below for more info).

• Where we have your **consent**.

• Where we need it to **perform the contract** we have with you.

• In order to comply with a **legal or regulatory obligation**.

The only circumstance in which we rely on **consent as our basis** for processing your personal data is when you agree to receive email marketing from STV or from the Scottish Children’s Lottery (operated by STV ELM Limited).

In the table below we have set out a summary of our activities which involve the processing of your personal data and our legal bases for doing so.

Most commonly, we process your personal data on the basis that it is in our legitimate interests to do so, or the **legitimate interests** of third parties with whom we share your data and we explain what those interests are in the following table.

PURPOSE/ACTIVITY | TYPE(S) OF DATA USED | BASIS FOR PROCESSING  
---|---|---  
To **create your STV account** and **provide the Services** that you have requested, such as, for example, access to the STV Player or to enable you to engage in interactivity with us (such as enter a competition or submit a Contribution).  |  Registration

Contact

Technical Performance of our contract with you. 

|  **Performance of our contract with you.**

**Legitimate Interests**

We need to know your postcode so that i) we can be sure that you live in an area in which we have rights to serve you STV and ii) to enable us to give you the correct regionalised version.

We use your Device IP address to identify your location, as for rights reasons, we cannot distribute some of our content outside of the UK.

We need to know your date of birth as you must be 16 years or over to open an account with STV.

We may also use your Registration Data in order to verify your identity, where you choose to exercise any of the rights listed in paragraph 9 below.  
  
To **manage our relationship with you** which will include, for example:

Sending you service messages, such as notifying you about material changes to our terms of use, cookie and/or privacy policy or provide you with password reminders; and

Responding to any of your comments, complaints or queries. 

|  Registration

Contact 

|  **Legitimate Interests**

To ensure a great user experience of our Services.

**To comply with a legal obligation**  
  
To **operate a prize draw or competition** |  Registration

Contact 

|  **Legitimate Interests**

To promote our Services through an enjoyable, interactive user experience of our Services.

**Performance of a contract with you**

We use your data to deliver the prize if you are a prize winner, and to publish or otherwise make available a list of prize winners.  
  
To **administer and protect our Services** (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data)  |  Registration

Contact

Technical

Analytical 

|  **Legitimate Interests.**

To ensure the efficient and successful running of our business, network security, investigation of any suspected breach of the **Terms of Use** or the breach of other applicable terms and conditions, and to help optimise your use of the Services and to give you a good user experience.

**To comply with a legal obligation.**  
  
To **improve our Services** , marketing, consumer relationships and experiences  |  Registration

Contact

Technical

Analytical

|  **Legitimate Interests**

To help us monitor, support and improve the performance, and your experience, of our Services (by analysing your use and experience of our Services and identifying any technical issues); to keep our Services updated and relevant and to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy.   
  
To **create profiles of our users** by bringing together the information we hold about you.  |  Registration

Contact

Technical

Analytical 

|  **Legitimate Interests**

To develop our Services and to help us understand more about which of our programmes and services you use and are interested in.

This enables us to personalise your use of our Services, and our communications with you, and to make recommendations to you about programmes or services that we think you may enjoy.

Knowing more about you also enables us to provide you with more relevant advertising (see the purpose below for more info).  
  
To **deliver targeted ads** to you based on the information we hold about you.  |  Registration

Contact

Analytical

Technical

Data from Other Sources 

|  **Legitimate Interests**

Providing our users with a personalised experience of our Services. In addition, advertisers place added value on being able to serve targeted ads (e.g. according to age; demographic and geographical information and your interests). This enables us to sell advertising effectively and to invest more into improving and developing our Services, and our content.

Note: If you would prefer not to receive ads on STV’s digital services that are targeted to you based on the information we hold about you, please log into your account and go to your Preference Centre. Please note that if you turn off this functionality, you will still see advertising, however it may be less relevant to you.   
  
Sharing of data with data processing companies who act on our behalf, to enable us to deliver our Services, such as those who assist with our registration process, host our data and provide other technical services to us.  |  Registration

Contact

Technical

Analytical

Marketing

Data from Other Sources

|  **Legitimate Interests**

To help manage your data, to provide analysis and to deliver specific functionality.   
  
Sharing of data with the Scottish Children’s Lottery, operated by our group company, STV ELM Limited  |  Registration

Contact

Technical

Analytical

Marketing

Data from Other Sources 

|  **Legitimate Interests of STV and STV ELM Limited**

To understand the use of our Services and those of the Scottish Children’s Lottery;

To tailor our communications with you;

To enable both us and STV ELM to deliver targeted ads to you.  
  
**4)HOW DO WE KEEP YOUR DATA SECURE?**

The security of your data is important to us. We have technical and operational security measures in place internally within STV, and externally with our authorised suppliers to protect the data we collect, use and store, against unauthorised access or disclosure; improper use, alteration, unlawful or accidental destruction or loss.

We limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

However, please be aware that the sending of information through the internet is not completely secure. We do not guarantee the security of your data transmitted to and from our Services over the internet, and you accept the inherent security implications of using the internet.

**5)SHARING OF PERSONAL DATA**

We share your data in the following circumstances:

  * When we engage data processing companies to act on our behalf from time to time to help manage your data, to provide analysis and to deliver specific functionality. We require those we share it with to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law and our strict instructions. Please note that some of these companies may be either located and/or have servers which are located outside the European Economic Area (please see below for further detail).

  * If whilst entering one of our competitions you have expressly agreed that you are happy for us to do so, we will share some of your details with the prize donor or competition sponsor of that competition. Please note that any shared data will then be subject to the privacy policy of any prize donor or competition sponsor.

  * Where we are required or permitted to do so by law, or to protect or enforce our rights or the rights of any third party or our users (which may include steps taken arising from a breach of our Terms of Use).

  * In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your data to the prospective seller or buyer, or new business partner.

  * When you join STV and also register for the Scottish Children’s Lottery, operated by our group company, STV ELM Limited, we will share the data we hold about you with STV ELM to enable a greater understanding of users, and to provide more relevant advertising and other customised marketing communications across our respective services.

    * We will only share personal data with STV ELM when you are registered with both STV and the Scottish Children’s Lottery.

    * If you are not registered with both STV and the Scottish Children’s Lottery, we will only share aggregated, anonymised behavioural information about your use of our services.

    * A copy of the Scottish Children’s Lottery Privacy Policy is available [here](https://www.scottishchildrenslottery.com/en/stv/footerlinks/service/privacy-policy.html).

  * Where you have given consent to us to do so, we will pass your email address to STV ELM Limited for the Scottish Children’s Lottery to send you marketing communications.

**Transfers of Data Out of the EEA**

Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the EEA to certain authorised suppliers providing functionality or other services to us, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented:

  * We will only transfer your personal data to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data by the European Commission.

  * Where we use certain service providers, we may use specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe.

  * Where we use providers based in the US, we may transfer data to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between the Europe and the US.

Please **Contact us** if you want further information on the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data out of the EEA.

**6)MARKETING**

We will only send you marketing emails about STV’s Services where you have given us consent to do so. Some of these communications are issued regularly (as is the case with our e-newsletters), others may be prompted by specific events, or programmes. Please note that these communications may be selected for you on the basis of information you have provided to us, and your use of our Services and may include third party advertising, or third party selected offers (targeted to your interests). Note that we may use your Registration, Technical and/or Analytical Data to form a view on what we think may be of interest to you.

You can unsubscribe at any time from email marketing communications or newsletters. Please go to your Preference Centre where you can manage the communications you receive. You can also unsubscribe via the unsubscribe link at the foot of any email, or contact us at [enquiries@stv.tv](mailto:enquiries@stv.tv).

Please note that if you unsubscribe from receiving email marketing from us You will receive service emails from us about your account or to update you on any material changes to our terms and conditions, privacy and cookies policies.

On occasion, when interacting with our Services, such as entering a competition, you may be asked for your permission to share some of your details to a prize donor or sponsor for their marketing purposes. That will be your choice, and at your discretion. To subsequently opt-out of receiving any such communications from a third party, you will need to contact the applicable third party. Please note that we are not responsible for the communications or the content of any communications you receive from any such third party.

Where we hold your address, we may from time to time, on the basis of our legitimate interests, send you marketing communications about STV’s products and services (which may also include third party advertising, or third party selected offers) by post. You can unsubscribe from postal marketing at any time by Contacting Us using the details at Paragraph 11 below.

If you download one of our mobile apps then we may send you messages, including marketing messages, via push notifications. You can disable these at any time by altering the notification settings on your mobile device or by uninstalling the app.

**7)STV APPEAL**

We host a micro-site on our Services that relates to the activities of STV Appeal, a Scottish Charitable Incorporated Organisation (Registered Charity SC042429) which has its principal office at Pacific Quay, Glasgow G51 1PQ. Although we work closely with STV Appeal it is an independent body for the purposes of Scottish Charity law. Any personal data we collect on its behalf is kept separate from any other personal data we may collect. STV Appeal is the relevant data controller of your personal data, and it is processed in accordance with STV Appeal’s own Privacy Statement which you should read before providing your personal data.

**8)LINKS TO OTHER SITES**

To inform and enhance your experience when on our sites, or using our Services, we provide a number of links to third party websites who apply their own privacy policies. Please note that this Privacy Policy will not apply to any such third party website. We do not control such third party websites or have any responsibility for them.

**9)YOUR RIGHTS**

You have the right to:

• **Request access** to a copy of the personal data we hold about you (commonly known as a “data subject access request or “SAR””).

• **Request correction** of any inaccurate personal data that we hold about you. Note that you can do most of this by amending your details via your account profile page.

• **Request erasure of your personal data**. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully, or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with a legal obligation. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.

• **Object to processing** of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information.

• **Request restriction of processing of your personal data**. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data’s accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.

• **Withdraw consent** at any time where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.

• **Make a complaint** at any time to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues ([www.ico.org.uk](https://www.ico.org.uk/)). We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please [Contact Us](https://www.stv.tv/info/contact/) in the first instance.

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response. If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please [Contact us](https://www.stv.tv/info/contact/) in writing.

Always keep in mind:

• You can update your personal details or change your password at any time by going to Your Profile at stv.tv or e-mailing us directly at [enquiries@stv.tv](mailto:enquiries@stv.tv?subject=Customer%20enquiry).

• Please make sure that you update your details as soon as possible with all relevant changes.

• You can close your account at any time by visiting Your Profile or e-mailing us directly at [enquiries@stv.tv](mailto:enquiries@stv.tv?subject=Customer%20enquiry).

• We will process your requests as soon as reasonably practicable.

**10)DATA RETENTION**

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes for which it was collected, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements. Generally this means that we will hold your personal data on our systems for as long as you use the Services, and for a reasonable amount of time after you close your account.

In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

Where you contribute content together with your personal information (User Generated Content or UGC) please refer to our Terms of Use for further information about how long we may store such material.

**11)CONTACT US**

We have appointed a Data Governance Manager who is responsible for overseeing questions in relation to this privacy notice. If you have any questions about this privacy notice or you would like to exercise any of your legal rights, please contact the Data Governance Manager using the details set out below.

Data Governance Manager

STV Central Limited

Pacific Quay

Glasgow

G51 1PQ

e-mail: [enquiries@stv.tv](mailto:enquiries@stv.tv?subject=Customer%20enquiry)

Updated: 22 May 2018

* * *

**Cookie Policy**

**INTRODUCTION TO THE USE OF COOKIES AND SIMILAR TECHNOLOGIES ON OUR SERVICES**

**WHAT ARE COOKIES AND WHAT ARE THEY USED FOR?**

**WHAT ARE SIMILAR TECHNOLOGIES AND WHEN ARE THEY USED?**

**WHAT TYPES OF COOKIES ARE USED?**

  * Strictly Necessary

  * Functional

  * Analytical

    * Combining Data from analytical cookies with other data

    * Broadcasters’ Audience Research Board

  * Advertising

    * AOB

    * Personalised retargeting

  * Other organisations’ cookies

**DIFFERENT WAYS TO MANAGE AND CONTROL YOUR COOKIES**

**MANAGING COOKIES IN YOUR WEB BROWSER**

    * Do Not Track (DNT)

**OPTING OUT OF MORE RELEVANT ADS INFORMED BY OUR COMBINED DATA**

**MANAGING ANALYTICS COOKIES**

**MANAGING ADVERTISING COOKIES**

**FINDING OUT MORE**

**INTRODUCTION TO THE USE OF COOKIES AND SIMILAR TECHNOLOGIES ON OUR SERVICES**

This Cookie Policy applies to our digital products and services which include our website (www.stv.tv); our STV Player App; our News App and our newsletters (the “Services”), regardless of the platform you use to access them. Whenever you use our Services data may be collected through the use of cookies and similar technologies.

In this policy we explain what cookies are, the types of cookies we use on our Services and what we use them for; that other people may use cookies on our Services; how you can opt out of viewing more relevant ads based on data we collect, including from cookies and how you can manage and control cookies.

If, after reading this policy, you are still struggling with cookies or want additional information on cookies we use on our Services, feel free to contact [enquiries@stv.tv](mailto:enquiries@stv.tv).

**By using our Services, without changing your web browser settings, we’ll assume you’re happy to the use of cookies and similar technologies as described it in this policy. You can change your web browser settings at any time.**

**Please note that we update our Cookie Policy from time to time, so please take a fresh read through every so often. If we make significant changes, we will make that clear on our Services, or by some other means of contact such as email.**

This Cookie Policy was last updated on 22 May 2018.

**WHAT ARE COOKIES AND WHAT ARE THEY USED FOR?**

A Cookie is a small amount of data which often contains a unique identifier that is sent to your computer, tablet or mobile phone web browser when you visit a website or application (“App”). If your web browser settings allow it, such cookies are stored on your device’s hard drive and are read by the website or App on each subsequent visit.

When you use our Services, the pages you view (along with a cookie) are downloaded to your device. This enables us to find out whether a device (and probably its user) has used our Services before.

Cookies do many different jobs. They let you move from web page to page efficiently. They allow us to collect data about your experience of our Services which helps us improve the performance of our Services, personalise your experience and make your visits and use of our Services as straightforward, efficient and enjoyable as possible. They can also help to ensure that adverts (ads) you see online are more relevant to your interests.

Some cookies are erased when you close the browser on your website or app. Others stay longer, sometimes forever, and are saved onto your device so they're there when you come back.

**WHAT ARE SIMILAR TECHNOLOGIES AND WHEN ARE THEY USED?**

Local storage performs very similar functions to cookies. It involves the storage of local files on the hard drive of the device you use to access our STV News App and STV Player App on AppleiOS and Android devices.

Like cookies, local storage can be sessional or perpetual.

Like cookies, local storage does many different jobs. It allows us, for example, to identify you as “signed” in and keeps you in a signed in state each time you use the App; to remember “resume” points in videos you have watched; and to manage parental control functions.

These locally stored files are essential to the operation of our Apps. It is not currently possible to opt out or remove these files from the device without deleting the App(s). For AppleiOS and Android, YouView, Samsung, Freeview, Roku, Now TV, Chromecast devices we send anonymous data to Adobe, our analytical processor, to track usage and for quality purposes.

When we talk about **“cookies”** in this policy we mean cookies or similar technologies.

**WHAT TYPES OF COOKIES ARE USED?**

The following types of cookies are used on our Services.

  * **(i) Strictly Necessary** cookies enable you to move around [www.stv.tv](https://www.stv.tv/) and our Apps and to use their features. They allow us, for example, to;

    * recognise which users are registered users of our Services;

    * identify you as signed in to our Services and keep you signed in throughout your visits so that you don’t need to sign in each and every time you visit;

    * remember security settings, such as parental controls, which restricts access to certain content.

If your device or web browser is not set to receive them, aspects of our Services will not work for you. Disabled parental controls, for example, will not work, nor will our Services be able to recognise you as a registered user, and you may not be able to use the STV Player or view our Live or On Demand content.

  * **(ii) Functional** cookies allow us to remember choices you made previously, when using our Services, as well as details, like your user name. That helps personalise your use of our Services and make it more efficient and enjoyable. Examples of the things functional cookies do include;

    * allowing you access to your stored information if you have joined STV;

    * remembering your settings on your visits to our Services;

    * enabling us to serve the appropriate regionalised service relevant to your location;

    * remembering your place in a video if you leave the "On Demand" section of our Services at STV Player before you've finished watching a programme, so that you can pick up where you left off the next time; and

    * limiting the number of times that some ads which you may view on our Services are shown to you within a short space of time. This is sometimes called “frequency capping”.

  * **(iii) Analytical** cookies are used in analytical services provided by other organisations on our behalf to help us to profile people who use our Services and to better understand how they use them.

Analytical services allow us to;

    * recognise your web browser or device if you have used our Services before;

    * count the number of visitors to our Services;

    * analyse patterns of behaviour among our users- see what parts of our Services are most popular;

    * test different versions of a page or feature and how information is presented to you to see which one works best; 

    * identify what programmes and ads have been watched online;
  
which, in turn, allows us to:
    * provide you with recommendations- for example, if we see that people who watched a programme you are watching also watched another programme, we might recommend that other programme to you;

    * deliver more relevant ads to you; and

    * improve our Services and deliver a better user experience.

**Combining Data from analytical cookies with other data**

If you provide personal data to us, such as your name, address, email address or date of birth, when using our Services, we may combine that with data we get from our analytical services and from data we collect from [Experian](https://www.experian.co.uk/) to analyse how our Services are used. Where combined data can be used to identify you, we use it only in accordance with our Privacy Policy.

We may use that data to (i) send you newsletters that might be of interest to you where you have opted in to receive such communications and (ii) deliver to you ads across our Services (including in our newsletters) that are more relevant to your interests. You may opt out of (or back in to) receiving more relevant ads from us based on Combined Data at your Preference Centre. Please note that receiving more relevant ads from us on the basis of Combined Data is not OBA. WE describe OBA and how you can opt out of it in the (iv) Advertising cookies section below.

**Broadcasters’ Audience Research Board**

We are currently participating in a research project carried out by the Broadcasters’ Audience Research Board (BARB) to gather anonymised statistics about the usage of media players. The aim is to understand the number of users and the extent of use of these players and the content within them. Several other major broadcasters are also participating in the project. BARB has chosen Kantar Media to collect this data through the use of cookies that are placed on your device when you use STV Player. All data is collected anonymously and will not be used by us for any other purpose but for this project.

  * **(iv) Advertising** cookies are set by our advertising partners. Some have functional purposes such as capping the number of times you see an ad, but most enable Online Behavioural Advertising “OBA” (also known as ‘behavioural targeting' or ‘interest based advertising') which delivers ads to you that are more relevant to your interests.

    * **(a) OBA cookies remember a user’s web browsing activity.** Shared interests, based upon, and inferred from, the websites you have visited, are grouped together. Ads you view will be determined by these interests. For example, if you visit a sports’ section of a website and searched other websites for sport, that interest – together with the shared interests of other web users - might be grouped together as ‘sport loving” and you may be served ads for sport and sports’ related goods or services.

    * **(b) Personalised retargeting** is a form of OBA that enables our advertising partners to show you ads based on your online browsing away from our Services. Therefore, when you use our Services, you may see ads for products or services from websites you have visited away from our Services. These cookies will usually be set by advertising partners that are working with many advertisers and ad agencies. Our main advertising partners are detailed in the Managing Advertising Cookies section below.

Without these cookies, online ads you see may be less relevant to your interests.

  * **(v) Other organisations’ cookies** may be set on pages of our Services where we include embedded content from other organisations like [Twitter](https://twitter.com/), [YouTube](https://www.youtube.com/), [Instagram](https://www.instagram.com/) and [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/). We cannot access or control these cookies. You should check the relevant organisation’s website for information about them.

**DIFFERENT WAYS TO MANAGE AND CONTROL YOUR COOKIES**

There are various ways that you can manage and control your cookies and we outline them below.

**MANAGING COOKIES IN YOUR WEB BROWSER**

You can block most cookies by activating the settings on your web browser that allow you to refuse the setting of some or all cookies. However, if you block all cookies you may not be able to access all or parts of our services, or you may experience reduced functionality when accessing certain services. Unless you have adjusted your web browser settings so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies as soon as you visit our Services.

The links below take you to the website of some of the major web browsers where you can find out more about how to manage cookies they set.

Android: <http://support.google.com/chrome/answer/2392971?hl=en-GB>

Blackberry: <http://uk.blackberry.com/legal/privacy-policy.html#types-info-d>

Firefox: <https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/control-center-site-privacy-and-security-firefox>

Google Chrome: [http://support.google.com/chrome/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=95647](http://support.google.com/chrome/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=95647)

Internet Explorer: <https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies>

Safari iOS: <https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201265>

**Other web browsers**

With new devices being created all the time, including tablets and phones, it is not possible to list every web browser for every device. It may be best to consult the manufacturer’s websites for further instructions regarding cookies.

**Do Not Track (DNT)**

Do Not Track is a feature offered by some web browsers which, when enabled, sends a signal to websites to request that your browsing is not tracked, (for example by advertising networks, social networks and analytic companies). Our Services do not currently respond to DNT requests.

**MANAGING ANALYTICS COOKIES**

Listed below are the analytics providers we use on our Services. Following the links will enable you to opt out of their cookies. You should note that opting out of analytical cookies will inhibit our ability to learn what you like and don’t like about our Services and improve them.

Organisation setting the cookie | Purpose(s) for which this cookie is used  
---|---  
Google Analytics |  Google Analytics is a web analytics tool provided by Google. Google Analytics uses cookies to help the website analyse how users use our Services.

You may reject or delete these cookies by downloading and installing the Google Analytics Opt-out Web browser Add-on available here: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>  
  
Comscore (acquired by Adobe) |  Comscore cookies are used for analytics which measure web and app activity data. A unique identifier is given to each device to allow log analysis to determine the number of unique users for various parts of the site. Data is only used in aggregate.  
You can opt out by visiting the Digital Advertising Alliance’s consumer choice page at: <http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/>  
Kantar Media |  This cookie helps us determine the number of unique visitors to the STV Player App, the programmes they watch and for how long. To opt out of having your anonymised activity collected for the BARB project go to: [http://optout.2cnt.net](http://optout.2cnt.net/)  
Adobe |  Adobe uses cookies to identify users and tracks their movements around our Services. They enable us to store information about, for example, the programmes you have watched online and, if you have partially watched a video, enable you to return to where the video stopped, to resume paying. You can configure your web browser to reject Abobe, or all cookies. If you do, Adobe, and others, will no longer collect information for them.   
Permutive |  Permutive uses cookies to identify website users and tracks users’ movements around our Services. To opt out of having your activity collected by Permutive go to: Permutive Opt Out   
  
**MANAGING ADVERTISING COOKIES**

You can turn other organisations’ advertising cookies off. Doing that won’t mean you will receive less advertising when you use our Services; just that the advertising you see may be less relevant to your interests.

We have set out below our advertising partners who set cookies on our Services.

Organisation setting the cookie | Purpose(s) for which this cookie is used  
---|---  
Adobe |  Adobe use cookies to cap the frequency with which the same ad is served within a period of time and to target ads demographically.

You can configure your web browser to reject Adobe, or all cookies. If you do, Adobe, and others, will no longer collect information for them.   
  
AOL |  AOL uses a variety of online technologies including cookies and similar technologies with other information it maintains to present and help measure and research the effectiveness of its ads and to customize the ads provided to you.

For more information about how AOL use data please see their Privacy Policy at: <http://privacy.aol.com/>  
You can opt out by visiting the Digital Advertising Alliance’s consumer choice page at: <http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/>  
  
Doubleclick |  Doubleclick (part of Google) uses cookies and IP address analysis to identify unique users of our website and to track the conversion rates for particular ad campaigns, to help serve ads which are of particular relevance to you, and to control the frequency with which particular ads are displayed to our users.

For more information about how Google use data please see Google’s Privacy Policy at <http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>.

You can opt out by visiting: <http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/ads/>.   
  
Google Ads |  Google uses cookies and IP address analysis to identify unique users of our website and to track the conversion rates for particular ad campaigns, to help serve ads which are of particular relevance to you, and to control the frequency with which particular ads are displayed to our users.

For more information about how Google use data please see their Privacy Policy at <http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/ads/>

You can opt out by visiting: <http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/ads/>.   
  
Group M |  GroupM uses Personal Data for purposes related to its online advertising activities, including without limitation (i) Interest-Based Advertising and modelling, (ii) bidding, optimization, forecasting, audience planning, creative strategy, and custom ad creation, (iii) providing inventory and other product offerings, and (iv) visualization, analytics and reporting. You can find out more and opt out here: < href="https://www.groupm.com/mplatform-privacy-policy">https://www.groupm.com/mplatform-privacy-policy.   
Index Exchange |  Index Exchange uses cookies for tracking when you have seen an ad.

You can opt out by visiting: <http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/>  
  
Rubicon Project |  Rubicon Project uses cookies to help serve ads which are of particular relevance to you. Rubicon Project collects certain information about you and your device. Some of this information (including for example your IP addresses and certain unique device identifiers), may identify a particular computer or device, and is considered “personal data” but does not contain your name, address, or contact details.

For more information please see Rubicon Project’s Privacy Policy at: <http://rubiconproject.com/rubicon-project-yield-optimization-privacy-policy/>

You can opt out by visiting: <http://www.rubiconproject.com/privacy/consumer-online-profile-and-opt-out/>  
  
Teads |  Teads uses cookies to recognize users’ devices in order to deliver the most relevant video ads (that can be based on your country, language, or interests for example) and to cap the frequency with which the same ad is served in a period of time.

For more information please see Teads’ Privacy Policy at: [https://teads.tv/privacy-policy](https://teads.tv/privacy-policy/)

You can opt out by visiting: [https://teads.tv/privacy-policy/ad-interest-manager](https://teads.tv/privacy-policy/ad-interest-manager/)  
  
Tribal Fusion |  Tribal Fusion (part of Exponential Interactive, Inc) uses cookies to help serve ads which are of particular relevance to you, to measure the reach of particular advertising campaigns and to control the frequency with which particular ads are served.

For more information about how Tribal Fusion uses cookies, please visit: [http://exponential.com](http://exponential.com/)

You can opt out by visiting: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/)  
  
Say Media |  Say Media use cookies to help serve ads which are of particular relevance to you, to measure the reach of particular advertising campaigns and control the frequency with which particular ads are served to users of our website.

For more information about how Say Media use cookies, and how to opt-out, please visit: <https://www.saymedia.com/fine-print>  
  
Criteo |  Criteo use cookies to help serve ads which are of particular relevance to you, to measure the reach of particular advertising campaigns and control the frequency with which particular ads are served to users of our website.

For more information about how they use cookies, and how to opt-out, please visit: <http://www.criteo.com/us/privacy-policy>  
  
Atlas (a Facebook company) |  Atlas uses cookies to help serve ads which are of particular relevance to you, to measure the reach of particular advertising campaigns and control the frequency with which particular ads are served to users of our website.

For more information about how they use cookies please visit: <http://atlassolutions.com/privacy-policy>

You can opt out by visiting: <http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/>  
  
Ooyala |  We use Ooyala to serve video ads. Ooyala uses cookies to identify unique users viewing the ads it serves. Analysis of this data helps to identify the number of unique users viewing ads, as well as controlling the frequency certain ads are shown. Cookies are also used for audience targeting using information that identifies you as part of certain audience segments.

You can configure your web browser to reject Ooyala, or all, cookies. If you do, Ooyala, and others, will no longer collect information.   
  
Spot X |  Spot X uses cookies to identify advertising campaigns eligible for delivery and to cap the frequency of an ad being shown to you.

For more information on how to opt out please go to their Privacy Policy at: <https://www.spotx.tv/privacy-policy/>  
  
**FINDING OUT MORE**

To find out more about cookies, including how to disable/enable them visit www.aboutcookies.org.uk. If you still want to opt out of these other organisations’ advertising cookies, you can do this by visiting the Interactive Advertising Bureau's website www.youronlinechoices.com which lists all ad serving cookies that are currently set on your device and tells you how to opt-out from each of them. If you would like more information on our use of cookies, you can always contact [enquiries@stv.tv](mailto:enquiries@stv.tv).

Updated: 22 May 2018

* * *

**STV COMPETITION, PRIZE DRAW AND VOTING TERMS AND CONDITIONS**

**Contents**

**A.** Introduction

 **B.** Eligibility

**C.** How to enter

**D.** Competition period

**E.** Conditions of entry

**F.** Prizes

**G.** Winners

**H.** Claiming the prize

**I.** Liability

**J.** Privacy

**K.** Use of materials submitted by entrants as part of their entry

**L.** Other matters relating to competitions

**M.** Competitions promoted on social media platforms

**N.** Promoter's details

**A.Introduction**

  1. These terms and conditions (“Competition Terms”) together with any specific ‘rules’ set out within any Competition promotional material (“Competition Promotion”) apply to all competitions, votes and prize draws (each a “Competition”) promoted on STV Services (being our television channels STV and STV2, our website, News App, and our Player).

  2. In the event of any conflict between the Rules and the Competition Terms, the Rules shall prevail.

  3. The Competition Terms may be amended at any time without prior notice and the updated Competition Terms will be published on the stv.tv website [stv.tv/competition](https://competitions.stv.tv/). You should read through the current Competition Terms before entering and/or participating in any Competition.

  4. By entering and/or participating in a Competition you are agreeing to be bound by these Competition Terms and additional Rules (where applicable) together with STV’s Terms of Use governing its products and Services (which are located on the stv.tv website at: my.stv.tv/terms-of-use/). In the event of any conflict between the Competition Terms, additional Rules and the Terms of Use, the Competition Terms and the Rules shall prevail.

**B. Eligibility**

  1. Unless otherwise stated in the Competition Promotion, any Competition is open to residents in the UK, Channel Islands and the Isle of Man aged 16 years or over, except:

(i) Any employees of any STV group company;

(ii) any person or employees of any company who is professionally connected with the Competition or its administration; or

(iii) immediate family members of (i) and (ii) above.

  2. By entering and/or participating in the Competition, you confirm that you are eligible to enter, participate and claim the prize and STV may require you to provide evidence to prove your eligibility. In the event that STV is unable to verify your eligibility, STV has the right to disqualify you.

**C. How to enter**

  1. No purchase is necessary to enter and/or participate in the Competition.

  2. You must submit your Competition entry or cast your vote in accordance with the instructions specified in the Competition Promotion.

  3. You should only submit Competition entries and/or cast votes on your own behalf, unless there is a valid reason that an otherwise eligible entrant is unable to do so and STV has agreed in advance. Should you require help with an entry, please contact STV at [enquiries@stv.tv](mailto:enquiries@stv.tv). See Clause N(2) for contact details.

  4. Unless stated otherwise in the Competition Promotion, entry to and participating in the Competition is restricted to customers who have joined and created an online STV account.

  5. (If you have not joined STV, you can find more information on our home page at www.stv.tv and join by clicking “Sign Up” on our home page. Our Terms of Use (covering all our digital Services), including our Privacy and Cookie Policies are available at: [my.stv.tv/terms-of-use](https://my.stv.tv/terms-of-use/).

  6. You must provide your name, email address, postcode and your date of birth to join STV.

  7. Unless stated otherwise in the Competition Promotion, there is a limit of one entry and/or vote per entrant.

  8. Internet Service providers fees may apply when accessing the internet. It is your responsibility to ensure these charges are paid for.

  9. You must follow the instructions specified in the Competition Promotion. Failure to follow them may result in your entry and/or vote being disqualified and any charges, where applicable, may still be applied.

**D. Competition period**

  1. The “Competition Period” is the period between the opening date and time and the closing date and time for the receipt of entries by STV.

  2. All Competition entries and/or votes must be received by STV within the Competition Period. Any entries and/or votes submitted outside the Competition Period will be automatically disqualified. Where no opening date and time is specified in the Competition Promotion, the Competition opening date is the date the Competition Promotion is published.

**E. Conditions of entry**

  1. Only valid and eligible Competition entries and/or votes received by STV will be accepted.

  2. STV will not accept joint entries and/or votes.

  3. STV reserves the right to disqualify you if your conduct is contrary to the spirit or the intention of the Competition.

  4. STV will not accept responsibility for any Competition entry and/or vote that is lost or delayed in transit, regardless of reason or cause.

  5. STV will not accept proof of transmission as proof of entry to and/or a vote cast in the Competition

  6. STV will not accept competition entries and/or votes that are:

(i) automatically generated by computer or completed by third parties or in bulk; and where relevant;

(ii) illegible, altered or tampered with;

(iii) photocopies and not originals; or incomplete.

  7. STV reserves the right to disqualify any entrant and/or vote when it considers at its discretion, acting reasonably, that any entrant has used improper technical means to submit any Competition entries.

  8. If STV believes, acting reasonably, that any Competition entrant is not an eligible entrant in accordance with these Competition Terms, or has otherwise breached these Competition Terms, STV is entitled to disqualify that entrant and/or exclude that entrant from participating in the Competition. By entering a Competition, you confirm to STV that all information submitted by you is true, current and complete.

**F. Prizes**

  1. Prize descriptions are as specified in the Competition Promotion.

  2. Where a Prize contains multiple components, the Prize must be accepted in its entirety. For the avoidance of doubt, the Prize cannot be separated.

  3. The prize is subject to availability, there is no cash alternative and STV reserves the right, in its absolute discretion, to substitute the prize with a prize of equivalent or greater value.

  4. Where a prize is supplied by a third party, STV reserves the right to replace the prize with an alternative prize of equal or higher value if circumstances beyond STV’s control makes it necessary to do so.

  5. The prize is not negotiable or transferable.

  6. You are solely responsible for any expenses not specified in the prize description and STV does not accept any responsibility for any such expenses.

  7. Unless otherwise stated in the Competition Promotion, prizes involving travel shall be restricted and will be the responsibility of the winner as follows:

(i) You will be responsible for travel to and from the prize destination and for any costs incurred. This shall not form part of the prize;

(ii) You will be responsible for ensuring that you, and any person travelling with you, are available to travel and hold valid passports (where necessary), any necessary visas and travel documents for the holiday in question on the travel dates specified.

(iii) You will be responsible for all travel insurance, holiday insurance and health insurance required or desired by you in order to use the prize.

  8. Where travel dates are restricted or specified, the prize is only available for travel within the restricted and/or specified dates, and where travel dates are not so restricted or specified, all travel and holiday prizes must be taken within one year of the date of the winner being selected. Dates, once notified to travel agent, cannot be changed.

  9. Prizes are awarded at STV’s discretion and no prizes will be awarded in the event of improper actions by or on behalf of any entrant.

  10. Where a Competition prize is provided by a third party (“Prize Donor”), you may be required to complete additional formalities with the Prize Donor, including, by way of example, completing booking forms or signing up to and abiding by the Prize Donor’s reasonable terms and conditions. STV shall not be responsible for any acts or omissions of the Prize Donor or any other third party. 

  11. Not all Competition prizes are suitable for everyone. For example, some prizes may consist of items to be used for physical exercise or leisure activities. It is your responsibility to ensure that you are suited to use any Competition prize as it is intended to be used and to ensure that you understand how any such items work and their intended purpose and mode of operation. If you are, at any time, unsure as to your suitability to use any Competition prize that involves physical activity, you should consult your own doctor.

  12. By entering any Competition, you agree to provide any additional personal information to STV, including your name, telephone number and address which is necessary for the purposes of contacting you to deliver the prize or for validating your identity and eligibility.

**G. Winners**

  1. In the event that a Competition winner is to be selected at random from all eligible correct entries for the Competition, that winner will be selected by either:

(i) an automated computer process that undertakes verifiably random selection; or

(ii) an individual who is independent of and not involved in the Competition or its administration.

  2. In the event that a Competition winner is selected as a result of a subjective evaluation of eligible Competition entries - for example, a photographic Competition, – the criteria for judging will be set out in the Rules. Unless otherwise stated, selection shall be undertaken by or under the supervision of either:

(i) an independent judge who is independent of and not involved in the competition or its administration; or

(ii) a panel of judges that includes at least one independent judge on the panel.

  3. Where the names of the judges are not published on STV’s website at [www.stv.tv](https://www.stv.tv/) for a period of 14 days after the Competition Closing Date, the names will be sent to anyone who writes to STV, within 28 days after the Closing Date of the Competition, requesting details of the judges and who encloses a self-addressed envelope to the address set out in Clause N(2).

  4. Where entries are judged on creative or artistic merit or other subjective criteria, STV and/or the Competition judges (acting reasonably) reserve the right not to select a winner, and/or remove or amend selection criteria and/or the structure and operation of the Competition if entries are not of the requisite standard.

  5. Where the winner is to be selected by STV consumers, unless otherwise stated in the Competition Promotion, the winner will be the contestant with the highest number of eligible votes.

  6. In the event of a tie-breaker, the Winner will be selected by an independent judge whose decision will be final.

  7. In the event that any Competition winner, after being selected as the winner, is subsequently disqualified from a Competition for any reason, STV shall, in its sole discretion, decide whether a replacement winner should be selected in accordance with the Competition criteria.

  8. STV shall endeavour to contact Competition winner personally as soon as practicable after the Closing Date, using the telephone number or email address provided with the competition entry.

  9. If any Competition winner cannot be traced or contacted after reasonable efforts have been made by STV or, having been contacted, the prize winner declines the prize in whole or in part, then STV reserves the right to offer the prize to the next eligible entrant selected from the correct entries that were received before the Closing Date, or may cancel the Competition and dispose of the prize in its discretion without any liability to that Competition winner.

  10. STV does not accept any responsibility if the winner is unable to take up the prize. In such circumstances, STV may, at its sole discretion, choose an alternative winner, selected from the eligible correct entries submitted for that Competition

  11. By entering a Competition, the winner agrees to provide their first and last name and county (or region) of residence for publication by STV or release on request.

  12. STV may publish the winner’s name and city of residence on its website at <http://www.stv.tv/>. Where the winner’s name and city is not published, it will be released on request. Any such request must be made in writing, within one month of the Competition Period, and the writer must enclose a self-addressed envelope to the address set out in Clause N(2).

  13. By entering a Competition the winner agrees to participate in any reasonable publicity and promotional activity required by STV and further agrees that STV’s may use your name and county (or region) or residence, image, audio and/or visual recordings of them in any publicity or promotional activity.

  14. The decision of STV or the judges nominated by STV relating to the winner selection is final and no correspondence or discussion will be entered into.

**H. Claiming the prize**

  1. Unless stated otherwise, the winner must claim the prize within 14 days. If the prize is not claimed or accepted within that period, the claim will become invalid.

  2. The prize may not be claimed by a third party on the winner’s behalf. Unless otherwise agreed, the winner should allow 28 days for delivery of the prize.

  3. The winner must inspect the prize on receipt and contact STV within 14 days from the date it is received and report any concerns about the quality or performance of the same to STV. Thereafter, the winner is deemed to have accepted the prize as delivered. Any rejected prize must be returned within 28 days, or such other reasonable period as STV may require.

**I. Liability**

  1. Nothing in these Competition Terms is intended to, or shall be deemed to, restrict your statutory rights as a consumer.

  2. Insofar as permitted by law and subject to paragraph I(1) above, STV, its agents or distributors will not in any circumstances be responsible or liable to compensate you or accept any liability for any loss, damage, personal injury or death occurring as a result of participating in a Competition or accepting any prize except where it is caused by the negligence of STV, its agents or distributors or that of its employees. Your statutory rights are not affected.

  3. STV does not promise that the online or internet services in relation to a Competition will be free from errors or omissions nor that they will be available uninterrupted and in a fully operating condition. The services may be suspended temporarily and without notice in the case of any technical issues in relation to any telecommunications or internet network, problem with any system, server, or software, or as a result of any technical malfunction, failure or repair.

  4. You agree to indemnify STV in respect of any losses suffered by STV resulting from any claim by a third party or any fine imposed upon STV in respect of any matter, arising from your use of our Services and entry into or participation in any Competition in breach of these Competition Terms, any Rules and/or our Terms of Use or from your violation of any applicable law or regulation.

**J. Privacy**

  1. When you enter and/or participate in a Competition, any personal information you provide will be processed in accordance with the STV Privacy Policy. Any competition information you provide to STV, in addition to your account information, will be stored for a period of two (2) years.

  2. Please note that in the event that you elect to receive marketing communications from a named Prize Donor, the use of your information by such third party will be subject to the terms of the Prize Donor’s privacy policy. A link to the privacy policy will be included within the Competition Promotion.

**K. Use of materials submitted by entrants as part of their entry**

  1. STV does not, unless we agree otherwise with you, claim any rights of ownership in any materials that you include with, or that form part of, your entry to any Competition and as such, as between yourself and STV, you retain ownership of your entry and you authorise STV to use your entry and any materials forming part of it, for the purposes of:

(i) operation of the Competition for which it was entered;

(ii) any publicity or reporting of that Competition or any STV Competition activities; and

(iii) selecting a winner for that Competition.

  1. For the purpose of this paragraph K(1), by entering into any Competition you grant STV (and third parties authorised by STV) a non-exclusive, transferable and sub-licensable, royalty-free, perpetual, worldwide, irrevocable licence (for the full period of any rights in your Competition entry) for STV to use, reproduce, distribute, display, edit, perform and adapt your entry and each part thereof, for use in all media whether now known or subsequently developed.

  2. Where you are invited to submit original material to enter a Competition, any materials submitted to STV by you must:

(i) be your original work; and

(ii) not infringe any other person’s rights.

  1. In particular, you confirm to STV that your entry and all materials that you submit: 

(i) will not infringe the rights of any person, including without limitation intellectual property rights;

(ii) will not contravene any entitlement to privacy of any person;

(iii) does not breach any obligation of confidentiality; and/or

(iv) does not contain anything which is libellous, defamatory, obscene, indecent, harassing or threatening.

  1. You confirm to STV that you have permission to use or feature any people, any information about any people, or other third party material contained within your entry. If any person under the age of 16 appears in your Contribution, you also confirm that you have the permission of such person’s parent or guardian.

  2. You will not transfer files which contain viruses or other technologically harmful material.

  3. STV reserves the right to verify that your entry complies with this Clause K.

  4. Please be aware that unless otherwise stated in the Competition Promotion, STV does not accept responsibility for the return of any Competition entries to Competition entrants. This includes those entries consisting of artistic materials or other materials of whatever nature. Please do not submit any materials in entry for a Competition if you wish those materials to be returned to you.

**L. Other matters relating to Competitions**

  1. All decisions of STV in respect of any Competitions are final and binding and no correspondence or discussion shall be entered into.

  2. STV reserves the right to hold void, suspend, cancel, or amend the Competition Terms where it becomes necessary to do so and at its sole discretion, and without notice and any changes will be an amendment to these Competition Terms and the applicable Rules.

  3. In the event of any issues outside STV’s reasonable control including, but not limited to, war, terrorism, riot, civil commotion, accident, breakdown, damage to machinery or equipment or technology, fire, floods, snow, acts of God, strikes, regulatory, legislative interference, ruling or decision which prevents STV from operating any Competition, or providing a prize either as originally planned or at all, To the extent permitted by law and subject to Clause I(1) and I(2), STV shall not be liable in any way for any losses or damages suffered or incurred by you as a result of any such occurrence.

  4. If you are unsure about any of these Competition Terms, you should seek independent legal advice.

  5. These Competition Terms are governed by and shall be construed in accordance with Scots law and the Scottish Courts shall have non-exclusive jurisdiction.

**M. Competitions promoted on social media platforms**

  1. By entering and/or participating in an STV Competition promoted on a social media platform, you are required to comply with the social media platform service rules, for example, Twitter or Facebook Rules. STV shall not be responsible for any acts or omissions of the Social Media platform service.

Facebook

  1. By entering or participating in a Competition on Facebook: 

(i) you agree that you are providing information to STV and not to Facebook.

(ii) you are required by Facebook to comply with Facebook’s Terms of Use. STV shall not be responsible for any acts or omissions of Facebook.

  1. The Competition (including the Competition Promotion) is not sponsored, endorsed or administered by or associated with Facebook. By entering and participating in a Competition using Facebook, you are agreeing to release Facebook of any responsibility of damages that could possibly occur as a consequence of your participation.

**N. Promoter's details**

  1. For Competitions promoted only on STV2 (our local television network of services) the promoter is STV Glasgow Limited (Company Number 429418) of Pacific Quay, Glasgow, G51 1PQ.

  2. For all other Competitions, unless stated otherwise, the promoter is STV Central Limited (Company Number 172149) of Pacific Quay, Glasgow, G51 1PQ.

  3. You can contact us in relation to any Competition by e-mailing enquiries@stv.tv or by writing to us at Competitions, STV, Pacific Quay, Glasgow G51 1PQ

Last updated: 22 May 2018

**Comments and STV House Rules**

We want your views but we also want to make this a place where people feel they can contribute without being shouted down. So we have a few simple House Rules which we ask you to respect. We reserve the right to take down or edit anything that we consider breaks these rules. These apply to any kind of contribution you make, not just to words but to pictures and videos as well.

  1. Stay on the topic at hand.

  2. Don't post anonymously.

  3. Respect others; disagree as strongly as you like with someone but don’t spoil your argument by attacking or insulting them personally. That also means no hate speech, profanities or what we perceive as discrimination against groups or individuals.

  4. Solid facts always back up an argument; so be as accurate as you can. Better still, leave a link to where you got the information.

  5. Don’t include personal information (such as addresses or phone numbers), yours or anybody else’s.

  6. Keep it legal – that means not defamatory, in breach of copyright, in contempt of court or in breach of privacy laws (see 5, above). Remember you are responsible for what you say.

  7. No spam, advertising, spurious links or anything misleading.

  8. We (that is, STV) welcome your views on our own products and services but we will delete material that is incorrect or just plain abusive.

If you see anything on our Services that you feel should not be there, please click on the word "Flag" on the Comment to alert us to it. You can also contact enquiries@stv.tv or phone us on 0141 300 3704. We will deal with it as quickly as we possibly can.
